

MIKE SN

Toronto, ON 416-276-3033



Linkedin Page



<u>Personal Page</u>



Personal Email

ABOUT ME

A self-motivated and hardworking individual with almost 4 years of experience as iOS Developer, supported by ongoing secondary studies including a Diploma in Mobile Application Design & Development. With a strong work ethic and commitment to ongoing learning, I am confident of adding value to any team.

Applications in App Store

DoltPal: App link

An application made in SwiftUI with many complex animations in which users can have a different experience of a ToDo app, all 3d renders and icons have been made by myself. The app is using CoreData in CloudKit with in-app purchases features. Try it, you'll love it!

BankingPal: in App Store review process (Ask me to send you TestFlight link)

An application made in SwiftUI uses CoreData and many complex animations which let users have a nice and beautiful interface in the Neumorphism design method, with this app users can handle all of their transactions in a single app easily in a secure way.

WalkingPal : App link

An application that uses CoreLocation, mapKit, CoreData and CoreAnimation to locate and track the users when they do activities such as running, jogging and walking outdoor and calculate their activity distance, their average pace and the time.

CurrencyPal: App Link

An application that uses real-time API to convert 32 currency with a simple and user-friendly interface.

Core Skills

- UIKit, SwiftUI, Combine, RXSwift
- Knowledge of iOS technologies such as Autolayout, Class Sizing, Autoresizing, Storyboard, Xib, GCD, Document Directory, Localization, NSUserdefault, Local Notification, Web View, UX standards.
- Experience with iOS frameworks such as Core Data, Cloud Kit, Core Animation,
 Map Kit, Core Location, AVFoundation
- Experience with MVVM and MVC design patterns.
- Experience with the Agile methodology and its Principles.
- Experience with functional programming.
- Experience with CocoaPods.
- Experience with SwiftPackages.
- Experience with WatchOS,TvOS.
- Experience with server less cloud functions.
- Experience with JIRA.
- Experience with Google Firebase and Firestore.
- Some experience of Objective-C.
- Familiarity with RESTful APIs to connect application to back-end services.
- Proficient in understanding of code versioning tools (such as Git).

Education

- Mobile and web Application Development for Mobile Devices
 Collège LaSalle, Montréal
- Bachelor
 Azad University

Professional Experience

SideKick Interactive(Montreal)

August 2021 - Now

Responsibilities

- Lead UI implementation designs
- Creating new style applications for App Store.
- Writing Application on SwiftUI.
- Use API from clients side servers.
- Using new architecture for applications.
- Bug solver and issue finder in application.

Freelancer (Mike Codes)

January 2021 - Now

Responsibilities

- Creating new style applications for App Store.
- Applications have been written in SwiftUI.
- Application using CoreData and CloudKit to store user data.
- Application using complex animations to give new experience to user.
- All 3D renders and 3D shapes has been made by my self.
- All graphs and shapes has been written or drew by my self through the Swift or Figma.
- Application has been written and upload to App Store by my self alone.
- Application has been approved by Apple inc and can be download through the links in top section or the links in my personal website.
- Participating in some of my old projects.

Dakia Digital (Montreal)

2020

(iOS Developer)

Responsibilities

- Wrote base of "HYPR Tribes" app .
- Designed developing native iOS code to maintain and adding functionalities.
- Worked on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- Conducted and contribute to design and code reviews ensuring standards are met.
- Worked with Atlassian softwares such as Jira.
- Made project from scratch.
- Used Cocoa pods and implement those into project.
- Connected project to backend services.

Parastoo informatique

March 2019 - July

2020

(iOS Developer)

Responsibilities

- Created some applications for App Store.
- Implemented CoreData framework to store user Data.
- Used MapKit and CoreLocation to ease user find and navigate the locations.
- Developed native iOS solutions.
- Used AVFoundation to provide movie player for applications.
- Redesigned UI from simple one page app to multiple functional pages.
- Used Agile every basis days.
- Built unique UI features with XIB files and Interface builder.

July-December

Sina Informatics Group

2017 - May 2019 (iOS Developer)

Responsibilities

- Designed developing native iOS code to maintain and adding functionalities.
- Converted an old Objective-C project to native Swift.
- Added universal search and drill down menu.
- Worked with QA team to enhance performance of the application.
- Worked on bug fixing and improving application performance.

February